Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we are covering a very important health issue.
我是Catherine，今天我们讨论一个非常重要的健康问题。
That's right.
没错。
We are, that's right, in case of an emergency, maybe somebody stops breathing, so we need
是的，我们，没错，在紧急情况下，比如有人停止呼吸，我们就需要
to apply CPR.
进行心肺复苏。
Now what is this procedure?
那这个程序是什么呢？
Well, let's take a look at it in Vocabulary Preview.
好吧，让我们在词汇预览中看看。
CPR in English is an acronym that means C, P, and R all stand for different words.
在英语中，CPR是一个首字母缩略词，代表C、P和R各自对应不同的单词。
The big phrase here is cardiopulmonary resuscitation.
这里的大词是心肺复苏术。
All right.
好的。
So you don't have to remember that.
所以你不用记住那个。
Well, that's pretty hard.
嗯，那挺难的。
What if you break it down?
如果你分解一下呢？
So what is cardio?
那么cardio是什么意思？
Cardio means it has to do with your heart.
Cardio意思是与心脏有关。
And then pulmonary?
那pulmonary呢？
Pulmonary means lungs.
Pulmonary意思是肺。
It has to do with your lungs.
它与肺有关。
And what about resuscitation?
那resuscitation呢？
That means to bring back.
意思是恢复。
So to resuscitate is to bring back to life.
所以resuscitate就是使复活。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a very popular procedure.
所以这是一个非常常见的程序。
You probably see it in movies when somebody almost drowned, the lifeguard performs CPR.
你可能在电影里看到过，当有人差点溺水时，救生员会进行心肺复苏。
Oh no, the love of my life has just drowned.
哦不，我一生的挚爱刚刚溺水了。
And then someone comes and they push their chest and they say, one, two, three, they
然后有人过来按压他们的胸部，他们说，一、二、三，他们
count.
数数。
And then the person spits out water and everything and they're like, I always loved you.
然后那个人吐出水和所有东西，他们就像，我一直爱着你。
All right.
好的。
So that's CPR.
所以这就是心肺复苏。
Why don't we listen to this dialogue, see what's going on and we'll be back shortly.
我们为什么不听听这段对话，看看发生了什么，我们一会儿回来。
Hello everyone and welcome to our CPR for beginners course.
大家好，欢迎来到我们的初学者心肺复苏课程。
First of all, does anyone know what CPR stands for?
首先，有人知道CPR代表什么吗？
Cardiopulmonary resuscitation.
心肺复苏术。
That's right.
没错。
We apply CPR in the case of cardiac arrest or pulmonary arrest.
我们在心脏骤停或肺停止时进行心肺复苏。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Well, basically if your heart stops pumping blood or your lungs stop pumping air, then
嗯，基本上，如果你的心脏停止泵血或你的肺停止送气，那么
we need to get them going again.
我们需要让它们重新工作。
That's when we have to apply this procedure.
那时我们就必须应用这个程序。
Let's begin.
让我们开始吧。
I need a volunteer.
我需要一个志愿者。
Me, me.
我，我。
All right.
好的。
Come here and lay flat on your back.
过来，平躺在地上。
Let's suppose this young woman has stopped breathing.
假设这位年轻女士停止了呼吸。
We must lift the person's chin so that we clear a pathway for air to get into the lungs.
我们必须抬起这个人的下巴，以便为空气进入肺部清理出一条通道。
Then we place our mouth over the other person's mouth and blow air two or three times like
然后我们把嘴放在另一个人的嘴上，像这样吹两三次气，
this.
像这样。
Wait, what are you doing?
等等，你在干什么？
You're a married woman.
你是个已婚女人。
You can't just try to kiss me like that.
你不能就这样试图吻我。
Ma'am, I'm not trying to kiss you.
女士，我不是想吻你。
I'm trying to demonstrate how to apply CPR in the case of an emergency.
我是想演示如何在紧急情况下进行心肺复苏。
Well, okay.
嗯，好吧。
No French kissing.
不要法式接吻。
As I was saying, we blow air through the mouth in this manner.
就像我刚才说的，我们以这种方式通过嘴吹气。
Once this is done, we must try to get the heart going again.
一旦完成，我们必须尝试让心脏重新跳动。
To do this, we place our hands over the person's chest and press down firmly two or three times.
要做到这一点，我们把双手放在这个人的胸部，用力按压两三次。
Wait, what are you doing?
等等，你在干什么？
You can't just kiss me then go for second base.
你不能先吻我然后直接上二垒。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a couple of pretty difficult words and phrases there, but don't worry.
所以那里有一些相当难的单词和短语，但别担心。
We'll explain them now in Language Takeaway.
我们现在在语言要点中解释它们。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
The first phrase we've got today is cardiac arrest.
我们今天第一个短语是cardiac arrest。
All right, so cardiac arrest.
好的，cardiac arrest。
Now cardiac, I think that has to do with the heart again, right?
现在cardiac，我想那又和心脏有关，对吧？
Exactly, your heart.
没错，你的心脏。
And what about arrest?
那arrest呢？
Well, arrest means two things.
嗯，arrest有两个意思。
Maybe you've heard of this meaning to arrest somebody, the police arrested someone.
你可能听过它表示逮捕某人，警察逮捕了某人。
Well, this means to stop.
嗯，这里的意思是停止。
So we're not talking about the police here.
所以我们不是在谈论警察。
We're talking about the heart stopping.
我们在谈论心脏停止。
So cardiac arrest means when your heart stops.
所以cardiac arrest意思是你的心脏停止跳动。
Okay, and another word that's right next to it, pulmonary arrest.
好的，另一个紧挨着的词是pulmonary arrest。
So I'm guessing again, pulmonary has to do with lungs and arrest stops so your lungs
所以我再猜一下，pulmonary与肺有关，arrest是停止，所以你的肺
stop pumping air.
停止泵气。
Exactly.
没错。
So cardiac and pulmonary arrest, these are two times when your heart or your lungs, they
所以心脏骤停和肺骤停，这两种情况是指你的心脏或肺部，
stop doing what they are supposed to do.
停止做它们该做的事。
All right, and interestingly enough, the heart pumps blood, the lungs pump air, and that's
好的，有趣的是，心脏泵血，肺部泵气，这就是
our next word.
我们的下一个词。
What is this word to pump?
这个词“pump”是什么意思？
To pump means to fill something with.
“Pump”的意思是往某物里填充东西。
So for example, the heart pumps blood to the rest of your body.
比如，心脏将血液泵送到身体其他部位。
That means it's always making sure your body has blood going into it.
这意味着它一直确保你的身体有血液流入。
And the same thing with your lungs.
你的肺部也是一样。
Your lungs help oxygen and air get to the rest of your body.
你的肺部帮助氧气和空气到达身体其他部位。
So they pump it, they fill up with air.
所以它们泵送空气，充满空气。
Okay, and we can do the same in other things.
好的，我们也可以在其他事情上这样做。
For example, you pump air into your tire.
比如，你给轮胎打气。
That's right.
没错。
If you have a flat tire, you're riding your bicycle and your bicycle won't move.
如果你的轮胎瘪了，你骑着自行车，自行车动不了。
Oh no, you have to pump it with air.
哦不，你得给它打气。
That means fill it up with air.
意思是把它充满空气。
Okay, or maybe even pump water, right?
好的，或者甚至可能是泵水，对吧？
Like in your house.
就像在你家里。
Or pump your car up with gas.
或者给车加油。
Okay.
好的。
All right, very good.
好的，非常好。
So now the man is going to explain how to perform this procedure, CPR, and he asks for
现在这个人要解释如何执行这个程序，心肺复苏术，他要求
a volunteer.
一个志愿者。
Okay, a volunteer.
好的，一个志愿者。
This is a word that can be both a noun, so a thing, and it can be an action, a verb.
这个词既可以作名词，表示一个事物，也可以作动词，表示一个动作。
Okay, so who is or what is a volunteer?
好的，那么志愿者是谁或是什么？
A volunteer is someone who offers to do something for free.
志愿者是主动提出免费做某事的人。
For free, without you asking them to do it.
免费，不需要你要求他们去做。
Right, so are there any volunteers in the room?
对，所以房间里有没有志愿者？
Right, and somebody says, me, me, me.
对，然后有人说，我，我，我。
Me, me, me, I do.
我，我，我，我来。
You can also volunteer to help people who need help.
你也可以自愿帮助需要帮助的人。
So for example, in Haiti, there's an earthquake, and there are many people who offered to volunteer
比如，在海地发生地震时，有很多人主动提出自愿
to help patients.
帮助病人。
So that means they said, I will work for free to help these people, a volunteer.
这意味着他们说，我愿意免费工作来帮助这些人，一个志愿者。
A volunteer, or to volunteer.
一个志愿者，或者自愿。
Very good.
非常好。
So now we have our volunteer, and the man is explaining what to do.
现在我们有了志愿者，这个人正在解释该怎么做。
Move the person's chin so that we clear a pathway for air to get into the lungs.
抬起病人的下巴，这样我们就能为空气进入肺部清理出一条通道。
This is a good one.
这个说法很好。
So a path is like a road.
所以“path”就像一条路。
It's where something can go, can move.
是某物可以走、可以移动的地方。
To clear a pathway means to make some room.
“Clear a pathway”意思是腾出一些空间。
To make a clear path.
清理出一条畅通的路。
So that means, think about it, if you can't breathe, someone has to find a way to make
所以这意味着，想想看，如果你无法呼吸，别人必须想办法
room to make a hole for you to breathe.
腾出空间，开个洞让你呼吸。
So that means to move whatever is blocking you to clear some kind of space.
所以这意味着移开任何阻挡你的东西，清理出一些空间。
So that's a pathway, a clear space.
这就是一条通道，一个畅通的空间。
And now, well he's demonstrating how to perform CPR.
现在，他在演示如何执行心肺复苏术。
So what is this verb, to demonstrate?
那么动词“demonstrate”是什么意思？
To demonstrate is very important.
“Demonstrate”非常重要。
We use this in most kinds of teaching.
我们在大多数教学中都会用到它。
So to demonstrate is to show or to give an example.
所以“demonstrate”意思是展示或举例说明。
Okay.
好的。
So for example, here in EnglishPod, we are demonstrating how to use these words in sentences.
比如，在EnglishPod这里，我们正在演示如何在句子中使用这些词。
Exactly.
没错。
So an example is a good way to demonstrate the word or the phrase.
所以举例是演示这个词或短语的好方法。
Very good.
非常好。
All right.
好的。
Why don't we listen to this dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
我们为什么不重新听一遍这段对话，一会儿再回来。
Hello everyone and welcome to our CPR for beginners course.
大家好，欢迎来到我们的心肺复苏术初学者课程。
First of all, does anyone know what CPR stands for?
首先，有人知道CPR代表什么吗？
Cardiopulmonary resuscitation.
心肺复苏术。
That's right.
没错。
We apply CPR in the case of cardiac arrest or pulmonary arrest.
我们在心脏骤停或肺骤停的情况下应用心肺复苏术。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Well, basically if your heart stops pumping blood or your lungs stop pumping air, then
嗯，基本上如果你的心脏停止泵血或肺部停止泵气，那么
we need to get them going again.
我们需要让它们重新工作。
That's when we have to apply this procedure.
那时我们就必须应用这个程序。
Let's begin.
我们开始吧。
I need a volunteer.
我需要一个志愿者。
Me, me.
我，我。
All right.
好的。
Come here and lay flat on your back.
过来，平躺在地上。
Let's suppose this young woman has stopped breathing.
假设这位年轻女士停止了呼吸。
We must lift the person's chin so that we clear a pathway for air to get into the lungs.
我们必须抬起病人的下巴，这样我们就能为空气进入肺部清理出一条通道。
Then we place our mouth over the other person's mouth and blow air two or three times like
然后我们把嘴放在另一个人的嘴上，吹两三次气，就像
this.
这个。
Wait, what are you doing?
等等，你在干什么？
I'm a married woman.
我是个已婚女人。
You can't just try to kiss me like that.
你不能就这样想亲我。
Ma'am, I'm not trying to kiss you.
女士，我不是想亲你。
I'm trying to demonstrate how to apply CPR in the case of an emergency.
我是想演示如何在紧急情况下进行心肺复苏。
Well, okay.
好吧。
No French kissing.
别来法式舌吻。
As I was saying, we blow air through the mouth in this manner.
就像我刚才说的，我们这样通过嘴巴吹气。
Once this is done, we must try to get the heart going again.
做完这个，我们必须试着让心脏重新跳动。
To do this, we place our hands over the person's chest and press down firmly two or three times.
要做到这一点，我们把双手放在对方的胸口，用力按压两三次。
Wait, what are you doing?
等等，你在干什么？
You can't just kiss me then go for second base.
你不能亲了我之后就直接上二垒。
All right.
好吧。
We're back so now let's go with Fluency Builder.
我们回来了，现在进入流利度训练环节。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Well, the first phrase in Fluency Builder we hear in the beginning of today's dialogue.
流利度训练中的第一个短语出现在今天对话的开头。
The teacher says, well basically if your heart stops pumping blood, then we need to get it
老师说，基本上如果你的心脏停止泵血，我们就需要让它
going again.
重新运作起来。
Okay.
好的。
So that's a whole phrase there, to get something going, to get it going.
所以这是一个完整的短语，“让某物重新运作起来”，或者“让它动起来”。
What do you mean by this?
你这是什么意思？
This means to start it up again.
意思是重新启动它。
Okay.
好的。
So we could say, I used to teach an English class for my colleagues but we stopped having
所以我们可以说，我以前给同事上英语课，但我们停
it.
了。
I'd like to get it going again.
我想让它重新开起来。
Okay.
好的。
So you'd like to start it up again.
所以你想重新开始。
Exactly.
没错。
So usually you're talking about turning something on or getting something started.
所以通常你是在说打开某物或让某物开始运作。
For example, maybe your car won't start so if you push it, you can get it going.
比如，也许你的车发动不了，所以如果你推它，就能让它动起来。
Right.
对。
To get it going or to turn the keys to get it going.
让它动起来，或者转动钥匙让它动起来。
Okay.
好的。
Right.
对。
So to get something going.
所以就是“让某物动起来”。
Now moving on, we have two key phrases here that are a little bit spicy, right?
现在继续，我们有两个关键短语，有点刺激，对吧？
Yeah, they're very romantic.
是啊，它们很浪漫。
Although this is a CPR class so it shouldn't be very romantic.
虽然这是心肺复苏课，所以不应该很浪漫。
All right.
好吧。
Well, this phrase that we have coming up is French kiss.
嗯，我们接下来要说的这个短语是“法式舌吻”。
To French kiss someone or a French kiss.
对某人法式舌吻，或者一个法式舌吻。
So the volunteer says, okay, I'm happy to help you but no French kissing.
所以志愿者说，好吧，我很乐意帮你，但别来法式舌吻。
Okay.
好的。
So what is French kissing?
那么什么是法式舌吻？
No one wants to answer.
没人想回答。
All right.
好吧。
What is it?
是什么？
It is when you kiss someone but your tongue goes into that other person's mouth.
就是你亲吻某人时，舌头伸进对方嘴里。
Ew.
噫。
All right.
好吧。
So there's a normal kiss.
所以有普通的吻。
You can kiss your friends on the cheek but a French kiss means that you use your tongue.
你可以亲朋友的脸颊，但法式舌吻意味着你用舌头。
Okay.
好的。
So I wonder why they call it a French kiss.
所以我想知道为什么他们叫它法式舌吻。
Maybe Americans just were too shy.
也许美国人只是太害羞了。
They blamed it on the French.
他们怪到法国人头上。
Maybe the French listeners out there can tell us.
也许在听的法国听众可以告诉我们。
All right.
好吧。
So now moving on and she says, okay, no French kissing.
所以现在继续，她说，好吧，别来法式舌吻。
Now the man is going to perform CPR and obviously he has to firmly press down on her chest to
现在这个男人要做心肺复苏，显然他必须用力按压她的胸口，让
get her heart pumping blood, right?
她的心脏泵血，对吧？
Right.
对。
This is a part of CPR.
这是心肺复苏的一部分。
So first of all, you try to give the person air so they can breathe and then you have
所以首先，你试着给这个人空气让他们呼吸，然后你
to push their chest to start their heart.
必须按压他们的胸口来启动心脏。
And this woman, the volunteer says, hey, what are you doing?
而这个女人，志愿者说，嘿，你在干什么？
You can't just kiss me first and then go for second base.
你不能先亲我然后直接上二垒。
All right.
好吧。
So what is second base?
那么什么是二垒？
Okay.
好的。
This is a sports metaphor.
这是一个体育比喻。
With baseball, right?
和棒球有关，对吧？
Baseball.
棒球。
Because baseball has four bases.
因为棒球有四个垒。
First, second, third base and home plate or home base.
一垒、二垒、三垒和本垒板或本垒。
Exactly.
没错。
So in romance, when we're talking about dating, we have a way to say first, second, third
所以在浪漫关系中，当我们谈论约会时，我们有办法说一垒、二垒、三垒
and fourth base.
和四垒。
First base is kissing.
一垒是接吻。
That's kissing, right?
那是接吻，对吧？
So second base, what would be second base?
那么二垒，二垒是什么？
Well, in this example, it means touching.
嗯，在这个例子里，它指的是触摸。
Touching.
触摸。
Certain parts of the body, right?
身体的某些部位，对吧？
Romantic touching.
浪漫的触摸。
All right.
好的。
So second base and then obviously we have third and fourth, but we're not going to get
所以二垒之后，显然还有三垒和四垒，但我们今天不打算
into that now.
深入讨论。
You can look it up on Google, third base and fourth base.
你可以去谷歌上查查三垒和四垒。
We trust that you can find it.
我们相信你能找到。
But first and second base are very common.
但一垒和二垒非常常见。
It's okay to talk about.
谈论这些是可以的。
It's not a bad word.
这不是什么坏词。
So you'll probably see it in movies, young kids talking about first base or going to
所以你可能会在电影里看到，年轻人谈论和一垒或
second base with someone.
二垒。
So it's kind of saying this in a different way, as a metaphor, as you said.
所以这就像你说的，是一种隐喻的说法。
It's more polite than talking about.
这比直接谈论更礼貌。
It's more subtle.
更含蓄。
All right.
好的。
So that's all the words and phrases we have on Fluency Builder.
这就是我们“流利度构建”部分的所有单词和短语。
Let's listen to this great dialogue one last time.
让我们最后再听一遍这段精彩的对话。
Hello everyone and welcome to our CPR for beginners course.
大家好，欢迎来到我们的CPR初学者课程。
First of all, does anyone know what CPR stands for?
首先，有人知道CPR代表什么吗？
Cardiopulmonary resuscitation.
心肺复苏术。
That's right.
没错。
We apply CPR in the case of cardiac arrest or pulmonary arrest.
我们在心脏骤停或呼吸骤停的情况下进行CPR。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Well, basically, if your heart stops pumping blood or your lungs stop pumping air, then
嗯，基本上，如果你的心脏停止泵血或肺部停止泵气，那么
we need to get them going again.
我们需要让它们重新工作。
That's when we have to apply this procedure.
那时我们就得应用这个程序。
Let's begin.
我们开始吧。
I need a volunteer.
我需要一个志愿者。
Me.
我。
All right.
好的。
Come here and lay flat on your back.
过来，平躺在地上。
Let's suppose this young woman has stopped breathing.
假设这位年轻女士停止了呼吸。
We must lift the person's chin so that we clear a pathway for air to get into the lungs.
我们必须抬起这个人的下巴，以便为空气进入肺部清理出一条通道。
Then we place our mouth over the other person's mouth and blow air two or three times like
然后我们把嘴放在另一个人的嘴上，像这样吹两三次气，
this.
像这样。
Wait, what are you doing?
等等，你在干什么？
You're a married woman.
你是个已婚女人。
You can't just try to kiss me like that.
你不能就这样试图吻我。
Ma'am, I'm not trying to kiss you.
女士，我不是想吻你。
I'm trying to demonstrate how to apply CPR in the case of an emergency.
我是想演示在紧急情况下如何进行CPR。
Well, OK.
嗯，好吧。
No French kissing.
不许法式接吻。
As I was saying, we blow air through the mouth in this manner.
就像我刚才说的，我们以这种方式通过嘴吹气。
Once this is done, we must try to get the heart going again.
一旦完成，我们必须尝试让心脏重新跳动。
To do this, we place our hands over the person's chest and press down firmly two or three times.
要做到这一点，我们把双手放在这个人的胸部，用力按压两三次。
Wait, what are you doing?
等等，你在干什么？
You can't just kiss me then go for second base.
你不能刚吻了我，然后就直奔二垒。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So a CPR class, this is actually a very popular thing to take up.
所以CPR课程，这实际上是一个非常受欢迎的学习项目。
You never know when you need to perform it, right?
你永远不知道什么时候需要用到它，对吧？
That's true.
没错。
I think it's a really smart class to take.
我认为这是一门非常明智的课程。
You can usually take them for free at a community center or a fire department.
你通常可以在社区中心或消防局免费参加。
The Red Cross.
红十字会。
I have a Red Cross certification.
我有红十字会认证。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
So you know how to perform this?
所以你知道怎么做这个？
Yep.
是的。
It's actually, as I said, I think it would be very useful.
实际上，就像我说的，我觉得这会非常有用。
I've never taken a course like this up, but I know how to perform the procedure.
我从未参加过这样的课程，但我知道如何操作这个程序。
I'm not certified though, so I'm not a certified CPR person.
不过我没有认证，所以我不是持证的CPR人员。
But it's interesting.
但这很有趣。
Let us know if in your country maybe you can take CPR classes or maybe you're a CPR certified
请告诉我们，在你们国家是否可以参加CPR课程，或者你可能是持证CPR
technician.
技师。
Or maybe you are trained in other ways, so we're curious about those as well.
或者你可能受过其他方式的训练，我们也对此很好奇。
Let us know if you have any questions about today's lesson, our website is EnglishPod.com.
如果你对今天的课程有任何疑问，请告诉我们，我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
All right, we'll see you guys there.
好的，我们那里见。
Bye everyone.
大家再见。
Enjoy 501c3PP0GRS today!
今天享受501c3PP0GRS吧！